## **Brandon Shurick**

Seattle, Washington ● +1.206.355.1535 ● brandon.shurick@gmail.com ● brandonshurick.com

#### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

A business-minded student of analytics, currently pursuing a Master of Information and Data Science from UC Berkeley, with experience utilizing statistical methods and machine learning to extract meaningful insights and create data products from large amounts of customer and operational data.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# TRAVELBIRD [AMSTERDAM]

June 2015 - June 2016

### Senior BI Engineer, Business Intelligence

- Created and deployed to production collaborative filtering algorithm using Apache Spark (with proven increases in email CTR 30%+ and order conversion 200%+)
- Developed fully-automated e-mail testing solution using Python and Vertica, splitting test and control groups and evaluating results across relevant covariates with statistical testing in Tableau dashboard
- Created dashboards for analysis of product AB tests and e-mail experiments

### WESTWING GROUP GMBH [MUNICH] Senior DWH/BI Developer, Business Intelligence

July 2014 - May 2015

- Measured primary contributors to churn and assisted with development company strategy for increasing engagement
- Deployed Vertica data warehouse, migrated from legacy MySQL system
- Automated and improved quality of many legacy Excel-based data management and reporting systems

## T-MOBILE USA [SEATTLE]

May 2012 - June 2014

#### Senior Engineer, Technology Product Development

- Managed Hadoop cluster to analyze handset performance data
- Created analytical models and dashboards for exploring and analyze handset performance
- Designed mobile software product requirements, led product development via managed software development vendor
- Presented product prototypes to top management to secure program funding

#### Senior Business Analyst, Customer Care Finance

**July 2010 - May 2012** 

- Analyzed customer call details and customer care agent performance metrics to uncover insights for management team
- Presented discoveries to management team in clear and concise format to assist decision making
- Measured performance of customer care projects and facilitated development of business cases to assist budgeting team with cost-reduction measures

## **Brandon Shurick**

Seattle, Washington ● +1.206.355.1535 ● brandon.shurick@gmail.com ● brandonshurick.com

#### **TECHNICAL TOOLSET**

TECHNOLOGY	PROFICIENCY	<b>EXPERIENCE</b>
SQL	Advanced	7+ years
Python	Intermediate/Advanced	4-5 years
Python SciPy Stack	Intermediate/Advanced	2-3 years
R	Intermediate	2-3 years
Django (Web)	Intermediate	2-3 years
MapReduce / MRjob	Intermediate	1-2 years
Apache Spark	Beginner/Intermediate	6-12 months
NoSQL	Beginner	6-12 months
D3.js	Beginner	6 months
Gephi	Beginner	6 months

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA [BERKELEY]**

**January 2015 - August 2016** 

Master's Degree: Master of Information and Data Science (MIDS)

**Coursework:** Storing and Retrieving Data, Experiments and Causal Inference, Applied Machine Learning, Research Design & Applications for Data Analysis, Exploring and Analyzing Data, Fundamentals of Linear Algebra, Fundamentals of Data Structures and Algorithms, Visualizing and Communicating Data, Machine Learning at Scale, Applied Regression and Time Series Analysis, Capstone Course

#### UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON [SEATTLE]

**September 2004 - June 2008** 

Bachelor of Arts: Business Administration (formal options in Finance & Information Systems)

Accolades: Annual Dean's List 2007-2008

#### **PROJECTS**

Data Visualization: Moral Reflection for a Better World (<a href="mailto:moralworldviews.info">moralworldviews.info</a>) ● Data Storage & Retrieval: Foreign Language Tweet Storage (code: <a href="https://github.com/bshurick/w205project">https://github.com/bshurick/w205project</a>, presentation: <a href="http://brandonshurick.com/w205\_FinalPresentation.pdf">http://brandonshurick.com/w205\_FinalPresentation.pdf</a>) ● Machine Learning at Scale Assignment - PageRank / Criteo Ad Prediction in Apache Spark (<a href="https://goo.gl/N6VUYi">https://goo.gl/N6VUYi</a>) ● Video or Text Math Education, Field Experiment (<a href="https://goo.gl/e0NfZZ">https://goo.gl/N6VUYi</a>) ● Video or